Hello everyone welcome back to the new video
I am your friend Nikhil and I have come with another
new video another very
important video on the EV space so
as you have seen in my title and thumbnail
this is going to be which is the best
insurance for you but not just the best
insurance for you but as an EV owner
what points should we consider
before we go ahead and buy an EV that
I am going to cover in this video so the
video will be interesting information if you are
thinking of buying an EV or
thinking of renewing your insurance
then this video will be helpful if you like it then
definitely give it a like if you are
new to the channel if you have not subscribed yet then
please do subscribe and do hit the
notification bell so that we get you a lot many more
videos in the future on that note
let's quickly get started let's get
[praise]
[music]
going so let's guys kuch ek cheeni gujna bahut
jaroori hai insurance company to select karna aasan hai guys who  The one who gives the
best coverage and the
best premium, we will select him
and
I will tell you at the end of the video who I have specifically selected or shortlisted.
What is important, guys, is that it is
important to understand that the insurance
company we are selecting for our EV,
specifically for EV, there are some things
which must be there,
they should be covered in your insurance premium, let's
discuss that, see there are some things which are
non-negotiable, that should be there in every company, it should be
cashless, your
nearby service centers must be a
part of their panel service centers, there should be
coverage of the vehicle in natural disaster and all that, and you should
get your unlimited claim,
plus it is important for you to know what is the
processing fee of your claim, it should be 1000 to 1500, it should
not be more than that, all these are
non-negotiable, I have
kept all these common, my three I selected are top three
I
found these things common in all three insurance companies. Now let's come to the important
point that as an EV, what should we
consider? First of all, battery and
motor protection. According to me, the battery and
motor protection that the company tells you, there is
no need to buy it separately. It is
a part of your base policy and the zero
depreciation policy is a green signal.
If any company says that besides the zero
depreciation, you will have to buy a battery and motor
protection separately. That's what you should
think in the comment section. The point is that
I should get my 360 degree coverage.
For example, I am driving, the
person in front of me suddenly applied brakes, an
accident happened, the rear end happened, two parts
of the car got damaged, will that
come under 360 degree coverage or the company will
say that we will provide insurance for only one side. So, it is
very important for you to get this clarification. Look guys, what happens is that
when we buy a car, when we go to our dealership,
they induce a fear there
that sir, buy it from us otherwise
later.  There will be a lot of hassle in getting insurance.
You can tell me in the comment section. Have
you faced this or not, they create a fear
that look sir, if there is some problem with the battery later then
we cannot do anything or with the
motor or something else, it is absolutely rubbish, do
not believe them at all, so you can be very stern with them
and tell them not to give
you misleading information. The
job of dealership and service center is to provide you
service, whatever condition your vehicle is in, whether it is
accidental or a
part of a damaged or accidental incident, or whatever it is, their
job is to provide service, they should get
money in return for the service, either you will pay the money
or the company will pay that money, so your job is to
select that the company which will provide it should be a
good company and for that we are making this video,
so it is not necessary to take insurance from the dealership only,
if they give a good rate then it is
good, generally see
what is the scam, that is for example
premium of Rs. 40000 they will quote you Rs. 70000
and then
What does this mean, I don't understand that you let me know, if you can wrap
your head around this scam which is
going on, it is very very wrong, so as I was
saying that just be very aware that
if any
dealership is telling you then don't get trapped, don't get trapped, if you
want to buy from outside, buy from outside, they have
told us 360° coverage of multiple parts, now some
companies are very smart, they
say sir, 100%
coverage on your parts in zero depreciation, but at a time if there is a
problem with two-three parts, then they say
no sir, in this claim we will give only for this part, so
you should ask them clearly,
brother, do you cover multiple parts or
not, once again, you should not get separate cover for battery and motor,
so whichever company is telling you that they will
give you a part of the zero depreciation,
take it in writing from the company,
so that it covers you  Have that peace of
mind. Now let's come to the ads. The
ads are very simple. They have a list of
ads. Meaning, what do they not provide in those ads
which according to me are not needed. So you should be aware.
You should be the best judge when you are shopping
for your insurance. You should see what you need and what you don't need.
For me, the most important add-ons are
number one return to invoice. That is the most
important because tomorrow if it is
my second or third year of insurance,
then my term already gets depreciated at 25 or 30. Then
return to invoice is an absolute must.
You can let it go. You can still take it. Take a
chance on day number one, but on
year number two and three and onward you must have
RTI. The next thing I believe is the tyre
protector. Yes, sometimes it happens that
if the tyre gets damaged accidentally, then
tyre protector key protectors are
not that expensive. It is a good thing to have. So,
I will probably buy this from because there is a company
whose insurance I  I will tell you in the end that they are
offering a package that if you look at the road side
assistance, then
I do
not consider anything more than this as an add-on, it is very simple
for me, you see which one is right for you, but
RTI in my knowledge, in my suggestion, there must be a
return to invoice for
road side assistance, the
manufacturer from which you are buying it,
you already have three companies for road side assistance,
see guys, there is a lot of
information, there are many such points
which I can tell you that this, this, this, this,
according to me, I have shared with you
that when I was searching for insurance,
I kept all these important things in mind because
I am searching for insurance for EV,
not for your normal combustion engine,
right, so there is still a stigma here, there is a
taboo that we will have to take separate insurance for this EV, so that should
not happen as per the rules, like combustion
EV insurance is insurance. As soon as
you take zero depreciation,
everything should be covered under it.
But okay, there's a scam going on. We're being fooled. We ca
n't do anything right now. If someone
wants to file a PIL, they should. I will be
the first person to sign it. So,
count me. And there's a number at the bottom of your
screen for
the top three companies that
I've shortlisted. SBI is at number three.
They quoted me Rs. 50,000 or Rs. 52,000
with all the add-ons that I
discussed, along with all the features that I
told you. SBI is at number two. ICICI has
quoted me Rs. 47,000 for an IDB
value of Rs. 16.1 lakh for all three, right at 95%
depreciation. So, I'm
well covered with ICICI. But one thing
they told me is that I'm keeping
them at two pay instead of one pay.
They told me that it's only in
case of an  Accident which
means a collision, your battery and
motor become part B of zero depreciation cover,
if while moving on the road, any
pebble, stone, nail or any sharp object
gets corroded, then they will not cover it and
here it comes under two pay, but otherwise
very good comprehensive policy for me,
ICICI guys you might say that y not
X YG company, there are many
and they all are good in my, for my choice these
three are better, so number one pay of ko was very simple, they were very
clear about what their
office was, they were very crisp telling me that
if your battery gets worn out or damaged by some pebble, stone or sharp object, it will all be
covered in that zero
depreciation cover, so I was very
confident and very happy and most
probably I am going to go with ko because the
quotation they have given me is
43000 so that too is less compared to ko  That
plus, look at the difference between Coco and ICICI.
Coco is new, it doesn't have that much reliability. It is
old and is quite reliable.
Their claim settlement percentage is very low, but
I have used Coco myself. There was a
video of mine, you can go to the link and watch it, in which
you guys have shown a lot of love.
Coco has many benefits, guys. It has an easy claim
settlement process. I have faced it myself
and I did not have to face any hassle.
Okay, so I am probably going to go with Coco, but then again
I am swinging between Coco and
ICICI. Meanwhile, look, Royal Sundaram is
following me a lot. It's a
great company. They are following up, so
I told them my requirements. If they can meet it, it's
great. Otherwise, most
likely, as I said, it's going to be one. So,
look, guys, as I said, it is as per my needs
and requirements. You will understand better what your
needs and requirements say.
Again,  If you need my
guidance, if you need my help, suggestions do, feel
free to book a consultation. There is a number
at the bottom of your screen and you can simply go to
my website which is there
in the description. You will find the link there.
Book a consultation. I will be
more than happy to discuss all your options, not only the insurance, but anything related to EVs or any vehicle. If you need any help, the guy is here for you. Okay, so I hope I have covered most of the things. I hope
you found this video helpful.
If you did, please do like it and
tell me in the comments section
what are your thoughts. Once again, thank you for all
your love and support in my recent
videos. It is really, really awesome and I am
very motivated to get a lot of more
interesting EV related information
for you. Also, one more thing to tell you, friend,
I am missing the combustion engine a little bit.  Of
our petrol and diesel
vehicles, whatever is the launch of some new vehicles,
we will definitely bring it
for you on the channel till then this is Nikhil
signing off, I hope you have
subscribed till now, and if you have not done it then do it
next time, friend, give this guy a chance and
see, he has to go a long way, 10000
subscribers on December 31, you have not forgotten, all
good, I will meet you in the next video, take
care, God bless, love you guys